RG 173:003, American Legion LaFlamme-Kusek Post No. 15
Connecticut State Library
American Legion LaFlamme-Kusek Post No. 15 histories
1925-1961
Connecticut State Library
Miner, Gilbert H
.5 cubic feet
Contains information on Post meetings and activities compiled by Post historian Gilbert H. Miner.
RG173_003
1993-030
Historical Note
The Griswold Post No. 15, American Legion held its organizational meeting in August 1919 and received its charter from the National Headquarters on September 6, 1919. At a special meeting held on March 15, 1920, the name of the post was changed to Orville LaFlamme Post No. 15 to honor LaFlamme who was killed in France in July 1919 during the fighting at Chateau Thierry. In October 1945 it was voted to again change the Post’s name to the LaFlamme-Kusek Post No. 15 in honor of Stanley Michael Kusek, the first man from Griswold to be killed in World War II.
Scope and Content
Contains information on Post meetings and activities compiled by Post historian Gilbert H. Miner.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
American Legion. LaFlamme-Kusek Post No. 15 (Jewett City, Conn.)
Subjects:
Soldiers -- Connecticut -- Jewett City -- Registers; Veterans -- Connecticut -- Jewett City -- Registers; World War, 1914-1918 -- Connecticut -- Sharon -- Registers
Places:
Griswold (Conn.); Jewett City (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
The history compiled in 1925 was presented to the Connecticut State Library through Daniel L. Phillips, Esq. on June 30, 1926. A photostat copy of the 1930 history was made on February 6, 1934 from the original copy loaned to the State Library by the author, Gilbert H. Miner. The histories from 1933 to 1961 were sent to the State Library by Gilbert H. Miner.
Container List
- Series 1. Histories, 1919-1961
  - History of the Orville LaFlamme Post No. 15, Jewett City, Conn. / by Gilbert H. Miner, Historian and Adjutant, 1925; 1 volume, typescript (Box 1)
    Covers 1919 to 1926.
    Contains "service records of as many men from the Town of Griswold, New London County, Connecticut as it was possible to get.
  - History of Orville LaFlamme Post No. 15, American Legion, Jewett City, Town of Griswold, Connecticut / by Gilbert H. Miner, Historian, 1930 December; 1 volume, negative photostat
    Contents: Part 1, History Orville LaFlamme Post; Part 2, Service Records of World War Veterans with index; Part 3, Cemetery records including Colonial Wars, Indian Reservation Wars, Revolutionary War, War of 1812, Civil War, Spanish-American War, World War, by cemetery.
    Spine states: 1914-1933.
    "This photostat copy...was completed at the Connecticut State Library February 6, 1934, from the original copy loaned for this purpose to the State Library by the author, Gilbert H. Miner.
  - Untitled histories (Box 1)
    - 1933-1942, typescript (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1942-1950, typescript (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1951-1958, typescript (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History of LaFlamme-Kusek Post No. 15, American Legion, Jewett City, Conn. July 1, 1958 to June 30, 1959, typescript (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History of LaFlamme-Kusek Post No. 15, American Legion, Department of Connecticut, Jewett City, Conn., June 1, 1959 to June 1, 1960, typescript (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History of LaFlamme-Kusek Post No. 15, American Legion, Department of Connecticut, Jewett City, Conn., June 1, 1960 to May 31-1961, typescript (Box 1, Folder 6)